# PANAGIOTIS PAPADOMITSOS CURRICULUM VITÆ

388 Beale str.
San Francisco, CA94105
+1 (702) 358-4128
http://ezgr.net
https://github.com/priestjim

#### **ELEVATOR PITCH**

Systems and Software engineer specializing in conception, design and implementation of distributed applications and their supporting infrastructures running on **GNU/Linux**, FreeBSD and Microsoft Windows operating systems with equal experience in leading and managing both development and operations-oriented teams.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Phlock Inc. :: San Francisco, California :: www.phlock.io

2015 - now

Co-Founder / CTO

- Responsible for the conception, development and implementation of the infrastructure supporting the Phlock mobile apps and web platform, the project's website and parts of the web application.
- Designed and developed the project's backend service in Erlang and C, focusing on superior image operations and user experience.
- **⇒** Tags: AWS, Chef, Splunk, PostgreSQL, NGINX, Lua, Erlang, GraphicsMagick, C, AngularJS, Gulp

**Splunk Inc.** :: San Francisco, California :: <u>www.splunk.com</u>

2013 – now

Head of Mobile Intelligence Cloud

- **⊃** Responsible for the conception, development and implementation of the Cloud infrastructure supporting the Mobile Intelligence product.
- **Development** Lead on a family of Erlang-based projects that receive and process more than 150.000 regs/sec from mobile devices all over the world. Holder of a total of 4 patents related to those projects.
- **⊃** Team lead for the Infrastructure Automation, CI/CD, Operations and Erlang Development teams, collectively managing 4 direct reports.
- **Tags**: AWS, Google AppEngine, Chef, Ansible, Graphite, Grafana, Splunk, Jenkins, Bamboo, Kubernetes, Docker, Erlang, Elixir, Git∕Stash

BugSense Inc. :: San Francisco, California :: www.bugsense.com

2012 - 2013

Head of Infrastructure

- **⊃** Responsible for the design and implementation of the company's cloud infrastructure and various supporting services.
- **⊃** Development Lead of the Erlang/C/Lisp in-memory streaming database that supports the company's "Insight Boxes" analytics offering.
- ♠ Member of the team that led to the successful acquisition of BugSense Inc. by Splunk Inc. on September 2013.
- **Tags**: AWS, Google AppEngine, Windows Azure, Chef, Percona MySQL, JIRA, Memcached, Redis, uWSGI, NGINX, Lua, PHP-FPM, Sinatra, Celery, RabbitMQ, Sensu, Ganglia, Mercurial, Git, Python, Ruby, Erlang, C, PHP, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Graphite, Riemann, LXC/Docker, Jenkins

#### dnHost Web Hosting Agency :: Athens, Greece :: www.dnhost.gr

Director of Engineering

2009 - 2012

- Responsible for the design and implementation of the company's cloud infrastructure and services.
- **⊃** R&D department lead developer.
- **Tags**: Rackspace Cloud, VMWare vSphere, Parallels Virtuozzo, KVM, IPv6, Percona MySQL, Memcached, Redis, Apache, OpenVPN, Asterisk, Bind, Litespeed, Tomcat, NGINX, PHP-FPM, Postfix, Zabbix, Ganglia, SpamAssassin, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Smarty, CodeIgniter, Yii Framework, XML-RPC/SOAP, jQuery, Subversion, Cisco Catalyst, Windows Server, IIS 7.5, ASP.NET, SmarterMail, R1Soft CDP

## Hellenic Lifeguard Academy :: Athens, Greece :: www.enak.gr

2005 - 2006 & 2007 - 2009

IT Director

- Responsible for the design, management and maintenance of company's network and system infrastructure.
- **Solution** Responsible for the company's online presence.
- **Tags**: XHTML, CSS2, MySQL, PHP, Joomla, Asterisk, Active Directory, Citrix XenServer, KVM, DansGuardian, OpenVPN

#### Wanderful Solutions L.T.D. :: Athens, Greece :: www.wanderful.gr

2006 - 2007

IT Solutions Engineer

- **⊃** Lead IT Solutions engineer, responsible for the design, implementation and support of small and medium scale internetworked applications and infrastructure.
- **Tags**: XHTML, CSS2, Asterisk, Windows Server, Active Directory, Microsoft Exchange Server, Borland Delphi

#### Operating Systems Laboratory, T.E.I. of Piraeus :: Athens, Greece :: www.teipir.gr

2002 - 2004

System & Network Administrator

- Responsible for the management and maintenance of the laboratory's server farm and application infrastructure.
- **⊃** Tags: XHTML, CSS2, FreeBSD, IPFilter, SunRay Terminals

#### Interactive Telecom S.A. :: Athens, Greece

2000 - 2002

System & Network Administrator

- Responsible for the management and maintenance of the company's local computer network.
- **Tags**: Microsoft Windows Networking, Windows 2000 Server

#### **EDUCATION**

Technological Educational Institute of Piraeus

2002 - 2012

Department of Electronic Computer Systems and Information Technology

## BSc in Electronic Computer Systems Engineering, GPA 7.45/10.0

**Thesis subject:** Statistical calculation of xDSL/ATM line parameters using online GIS systems

**Honors:** Admission scholarship, after achieving 6th place in admission order.

TALKS

Erlang Factory SF Bay 2016, San Francisco

March 10th, 2016

Subject: Improving RPC calls in Erlang and Elixir

ErLounge Erlang Meetup, San Francisco

April 14th, 2014

**Subject:** Introducing the Cloud Data Collector for IoT

OpenFest F/OSS Symposium, T.E.I. of Piraeus

December 14th to 15th, 2002

**Subject:** Design and implementation of a university's lab IT infrastructure using Free and Open Source Software.

SEMINARS

EuRuKo 2013 Badminton Theater, Athens

May 2013

FOSSCOMM 2013 Charokopio University

May 2013

Install, configure and manage VMWare vSphere 4.1 Performance V.A.D.

December 2010

HP Certified Professional Hewlett-Packard Hellas

January - March 2007

OpenFest F/OSS Symposium

T.E.I. of Piraeus, Athens

December 14<sup>th</sup> to 15<sup>th</sup>, 2002

GRNet F/OSS Symposium Holiday Inn Hotel, Athens

June 27<sup>th</sup>, 2002

### OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

• Scientific associate for Packt Publishing, recently reviewed "Mastering Chef" by Mayank Joshi.

- Member of the Athens Wireless Metropolitan Network (A.W.M.N.) with Node ID #4813.
- ⇒ Regular speaker at the Erlang San Francisco meetup.

#### FOREIGN LANGUAGES

**English** Mother-tongue fluency in both written and oral level.

**Certifications** Certificate of Proficiency in English, University of Cambridge

**French** Fluent in both written and oral level.

Certifications IFA DELF 2

**Greek** Mother-tongue fluency in both written and oral level.

## PERSONAL INTERESTS

Astronomy, literature, photography, fingerstyle guitar, ice hockey, snowboarding.